Hong-Kyun Bae

♥ IT/BT Building-718, Hanyang University, Seoul, Republic of Korea 04763 ⋈ hongkyun@hanyang.ac.kr (+82-10-6361-6854)

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Proven excellence in data mining and recommender systems research demonstrated through *extensive publication in BK21-recongnized top conferences* and *SCI(E)* journals, along with numerous *international* and *domestic patents* granted/filed. Holds a Ph.D. and a B.S. in Computer Science.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Sep. 2016 – Aug. 2024

Hanyang University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

Advisor: Prof. Sang-Wook Kim, Hanyang University

B.S. in Computer Science

Mar. 2009 - Aug. 2016

Inha University, Incheon, Republic of Korea

EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher

Sep. 2024 – Present

Hanyang University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

Visiting Scholar

Sep. 2023 – Dec. 2023

The Pennsylvania State University, State College, PA, USA

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Data mining; Recommender systems; Deep learning

INTERNATIONAL PUBLICATIONS

JOURNAL PAPERS

[j1] Hong-Kyun Bae, Hyung-Ook Kim, Won-Yong Shin, and Sang-Wook Kim, "How to Get Consensus with Neighbors?: Rating Standardization for Accurate Collaborative Filtering," <u>Knowledge-Based Systems</u>, Vol. 234, pp. 1-13, Dec. 2021. (SCIE, IF (JCR 2023): 7.2, Top 15%)

CONFERENCE PAPERS

- [c11] <u>Hong-Kyun Bae*</u>, Hae-Ri Jang*, Yang-Sae Moon, and Sang-Wook Kim, "Item-Ranking Promotion in Recommender Systems," In *Companion Proceeding of the ACM Web Conference* (<u>ACM_WWW</u>) pp. 505-508, Singapore, Singapore, May 13-17, 2024. (* co-first authors with equal contribution) (Short paper) (BK21 IF: 4)
- [c10] Jeewon Ahn, <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>, and Sang-Wook Kim, "Is the 'Impression Log' Beneficial to Evaluating News Recommender Systems? No, it is Not," In *Companion Proceeding of the ACM Web Conference* (<u>ACM_WWW</u>) pp. 822-825, Singapore, Singapore, May 13-17, 2024. (Short paper) (BK21 IF: 4)
- [c9] <u>Hong-Kyun Bae*</u>, Yebeen Kim*, Hyunjoon Kim, and Sang-Wook Kim, "Negative Sampling in Next-POI Recommendations: Observation, Approach, and Evaluation," In *Proceeding of the ACM Web Conference* (ACM WWW) pp. 3888-3899, Singapore, Singapore, May 13-17, 2024. (* co-first authors with equal contribution) (Full paper) (BK21 IF: 4)

- [c8] Jeewon Ahn*, <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>*, and Sang-Wook Kim, "Is the Impression Log Beneficial to Effective Model Training in News Recommender Systems? No, It's NOT," In *Proceeding of the ACM Web Conference* (<u>ACM WWW</u>) pp. 61-64, Austin, TX, USA, April 30-May 4, 2023. (* co-first authors with equal contribution) (Short paper) (BK21 IF: 4)
- [c7] <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>, Yeon-Chang Lee, Kyungsik Han, and Sang-Wook Kim, "A Competition-Aware Approach to Accurate TV Show Recommendation," In *Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering* (IEEE ICDE) pp., Anaheim, CA, USA, April 3-7, 2023. (accepted to appear) (Full paper) (BK21 IF: 3)
- [c6] <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>, Jeewon Ahn, Dongwon Lee, and Sang-Wook Kim, "LANCER: A Lifetime-Aware News Recommender System," In *Proceeding of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence* (<u>AAAI</u>) pp., Washington DC, USA, February 7-14, 2023. (accepted to appear) (Full paper) (BK21 IF: 4)
- [c5] <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>, Jeewon Ahn, and Sang-Wook Kim, "A Comparative Study for State-of-the-Art News Recommendation Methods," In *Proceeding of the International Conference on Next Generation Computing* (<u>ICNGC</u>) pp. 140-142, Jeju, Korea, October 13-16, 2022. (Short paper)
- [c4] Hongjun Lim*, Yeon-Chang Lee*, Jin-Seo Lee, Sanggyu Han, Seunghyeon Kim, Yeongjong Jeong, Changbong Kim, Jaehun Kim, Sunghoon Han, Solbi Choi, Hanjong Ko, Dokyeong Lee, Jaeho Choi, Yungi Kim, Hong-Kyun Bae, Taeho Kim, Jeewon Ahn, Hyun-Soung You, and Sang-Wook Kim, "AiRS: A Large-Scale Recommender System at NAVER News," In Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering (IEEE ICDE) pp. 3386-3398, Virtual Conference, May 9-12, 2022. (Full paper) (BK21 IF: 3)
- [c3] Sung-Jun Park*, Dong-Kyu Chae*, <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>, Sumin Park and Sang-Wook Kim, "Reinforcement Learning over Sentiment-Augmented Knowledge Graphs towards Accurate and Explainable Recommendation," In *Proceeding of the ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining* (<u>ACM WSDM</u>) pp. 784-793, Virtual Conference, February 21-25, 2022. (Full paper) (BK21 IF: 3)
- [c2] Yunyong Ko, Jae-Seo Yu, <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>, Yongjun Park, Dongwon Lee, and Sang-Wook Kim, "MASCOT: A Quantization Framework for Efficient Matrix Factorization in Recommender Systems," In *Proceeding of the IEEE International Conference on Data Mining* (<u>IEEE ICDM</u>) pp., Virtual Conference, December 7-10, 2021. (Full paper) (BK21 IF: 3)
- [c1] <u>Hong-Kyun Bae</u>, Yeon-Chang Lee, and Sang-Wook Kim, "TV Show Recommendation: Methods and Evaluation," In *Proceeding of the International Conference on Convergence Content* (<u>ICCC</u>) pp. 413-414, Busan, Korea, November 12-14, 2020. (Short paper)

DOMESTIC PUBLICATIONS

JOURNAL PAPERS

[j1] "익스플리싯 피드백 환경에서 추천 시스템을 위한 최신 지식증류기법들에 대한 성능 및 정확도 평가," 스마트미디 어저널 Vol.12, No.9, pp. 89-94, Oct. 2023.

CONFERENCE PAPERS

[c10] "이윤 고려 추천 시스템에 대한 비교 평가 (Profit-Aware Recommender Systems: A Comparative Study)," 한 국정보처리학회 춘계학술대회 (Annual Spring Conference of KIPS 2023), pp. 501-503, May 18-20, 2023. (Excellent Paper Award)

- [c9] "체크인 시퀀스 기반의 Next POI 추천 시스템을 위한 네거티브 샘플링 방법 (A Negative Sampling Method for Next POI Recommender Systems Based on Check-in Sequences)," 한국정보처리학회 춘계학술대회 (Annual Spring Conference of KIPS 2023), pp. 470-472, May 18-20, 2023. (Excellent Paper Award)
- [c8] "차량 운전자의 내비게이션 사용 이력 데이터셋을 활용한 개인화 POI 추천 시스템 (A Personalized POI Recommender System Using Driver's Navigation History)," 한국컴퓨터종합학술대회 (Korea Computer Congress 2022), pp. 564-566, June 29-July 1, 2022.
- [c7] "다중 클래스 환경의 추천 시스템을 위한 지식 증류 기법들의 비교 분석 (Knowledge Distillation for Recommender Systems in Multi-Class Settings: Methods and Evaluation)," 한국정보처리학회 춘계학술대회 (Annual Spring Conference of KIPS 2022), pp. 356-358, May 19-21, 2022.
- [c6] "멀티 클래스 환경에서 추천을 위한 지식 증류를 이용하는 딥러닝 기반의 행렬 분해 기법 (Deep Learning-based Matrix Factorization with Knowledge Distillation for Recommendation in Multi-Class Environment)," 한국 컴퓨터종합학술대회 (Korea Computer Congress 2021), pp. 1990-1992, June 23-25, 2021. (*Participation Award*)
- [c5] "추천 시스템에서의 효율적인 행렬 분해 모델을 위한 정밀도 변환 기법 (Precision Switching for Efficient Matrix Factorization in Recommender Systems)," 한국정보처리학회 춘계학술대회 (Annual Spring Conference of KIPS 2021), pp. 314-315, May 14-15, 2021.
- [c4] "다중클래스 피드백을 이용한 지식증류기법 기반의 추천시스템 정확도 평가 (On Evaluating Recommender Systems with Knowledge Distillation in Multi-Class Feedback Environment)," 한국정보처리학회 춘계학술대 회 (Annual Spring Conference of KIPS 2021), pp. 310-311, May 14-15, 2021.
- [c3] "객체 간 관계 정보를 포함하는 지식 그래프 구축 기법 및 추천 시스템에서의 활용 방안 (An Approach to Constructing Knowledge Graph for Recommender Systems based on Object Relations)," 한국정보처리학회 추계학술대회 (Annual Conference of KIPS 2020), pp. 759-760, November 6-7, 2020.
- [c2] "랜덤워크 기법을 위한 GPU 기반 희소행렬 벡터 곱셈 방안에 대한 성능 평가 (GPU-based Sparse Matrix-Vector Multiplication Schemes for Random Walk with Restart: A Performance Study)," 한국정보처리학회 추계학술 대회 (Annual Conference of KIPS 2020), pp. 96-97, November 6-7, 2020.
- [c1] "협업 필터링을 위한 듀얼 벡터 표기 방식 기반 오토인코더 (Dual Representation-based Autoencoder for Collaborative Filtering)," 한국소프트웨어종합학술대회 (Korea Software Congress 2019), pp. 99-101, December 18-20, 2019. (Best Paper Award)

PATENTS

INTERNATIONAL PATENTS

- [p2] "Method for Optimizing Performance of Algorithm Using Precision Scaling," Registration number: US11537395, Registration date: December 27, 2022. (USA)
- [p1] "Method and System for Knowledge Distillation Technique in Multiple Class Collaborative Filtering Environment," Application number: 17/979,487, Application date: November 2, 2022. (USA)

DOMESTIC PATENTS

[p10] "감정 요소가 결합된 지식 그래프와 강화학습을 이용한 설명 가능한 추천 시스템 (Incorporating Sentiment on Relations into Knowledge Graph and Reinforcement Learning towards Explainable Recommendation)," Registration number: 10-2633688, Registration date: January 31, 2024.

- [p9] "정밀도 스케일링을 적용한 추천 알고리즘 성능 최적화 기법 (Optimization Method of Recommendation Algorithm using Precision Scaling)," Registration number: 10-2380437, Registration date: March 25, 2022.
- [p8] "경쟁 기반의 TV 프로그램 추천 방법 및 그 시스템 (A Competition-Aware Approach to Accurate TV Show Recommendation)," Registration number: 10-2372712, Registration date: March 4, 2022.
- [p7] "효과적인 협업필터링 기반 추천시스템을 위하여 이웃의 평점 정보를 이용하는 평점 표준화 방법 (Method and Apparatus for Recommending Items based on Standardized Ratings)," Registration number: 10-2200340, Registration date: January 4, 2021.
- [p6] "추천 시스템의 이윤 최대화를 위한 리스트 별 순위 학습 방법 및 그 시스템 (A List-wise Learning-to-Rank Framework for Profit Maximization of Recommender Systems)," Application number: 10-2024-0036326, Application date: March 15, 2024.
- [p5] "Next-POI 추천을 위한 네거티브 POI 샘플링 방법 및 그 시스템 (A Negative POI Sampling Method for Next-POI Recommender Systems)," Application number: 10-2024-0036325, Application date: March 15, 2024.
- [p4] "아이템 랭킹 승격 기반의 추천 방법 및 그 시스템 (Item-Ranking Promotion in Recommender Systems)," Application number: 10-2023-0116596, Application date: September 4, 2023.
- [p3] "수명 기반의 뉴스 추천 방법 및 그 시스템 (A Lifetime-Aware News Recommender System)," Application number: 10-2023-0064160, Application date: May 18, 2023.
- [p2] "다중 클래스 협업 필터링 환경에서 지식증류기법 사용을 위한 방법 및 장치 (A Collaborative Filtering with Knowledge Distillation in Multi-class Feedback Environment)," Application number: 10-2022-0074989, Application date: June 20, 2022.
- [p1] "추천시스템에서의 효율적인 행렬 분해를 위한 양자화 프레임워크 (A Quantization Framework for Efficient Matrix Factorization in Recommender Systems)," Application number: 10-2021-0184046, Application date: December 21, 2021.

PROJECTS

- Institute of Information & Communications Technology Planning & Evaluation (IITP), "A High-Performance Big-Hypergraph Mining Platform for Real-World Downstream Tasks," January 2023 – Present.
- Institute of Information & Communications Technology Planning & Evaluation (IITP), "Development of Smart Media Analysis Techniques based on Implicit Feedback Information," April 2022 August 2024.
- National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF), "The Big-Data Real-Time System of Social Phenomena Monitoring and Social Simulation for Risk Management of a Hyper-Connected Society," March 2022 – February 2024.
- NAVER Company, '네이버 AI 뉴스 추천 알고리즘의 사용자 만족도 및 공정성에 관한 연구,' November 2020 November 2021.
- National Research Foundation of Korean (NRF), '데이터/기술 융합을 통한 네트워크 강화 및 소셜 네트워크 분석으로
 의 응용,' March 2020 February 2023.
- Hyundai Motor Company, "VCRM Data Analysis for Connected Car Services," August 2021 March 2023.
- Samsung Science & Technology Foundation, "Compiler-based Runtime Optimization Framework for Accelerating Multiple Machine Learning Applications," June 2019 May 2022.
- NAVER Company, '네이버 추천 서비스를 위한 One-Class Collaborative Filtering 기술 개발 연구,' August 2018 August 2019.
- National Research Foundation of Korean (NRF), '데이터/기술 융합을 통한 무관심 상품의 도출 및 이를 활용한 추천 시스템 기술 개발,' March 2017 February 2020.

HONORS & AWARDS

- August 2024, **Outstanding Ph.D. Dissertation Award**, The Research Institute of Industrial Science, Hanyang University
- June 2024, Invited Paper Presenter Selection, Korea Computer Congress (KCC 2024)
- June 2023, Invited Paper Presenter Selection, Korea Computer Congress (KCC 2023)
- May 2023, Excellent Paper Award, Annual Spring Conference of KIPS (ASK 2023)
- May 2023, Excellent Paper Award, Annual Spring Conference of KIPS (ASK 2023)
- June 2021, Participation Award, Korea Computer Congress (KCC 2021)
- December 2019, **Best Paper Award**, Korea Software Congress (KSC 2019)

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Program Committee Member: ACM SAC 2024 (SONAMA track)
- External Reviewer: IEEE ICDM 2023, ACM WWW 2024, ACM SIGIR 2024, IEEE ICDM 2024